# Nyrell Leonor

Experienced retail & logistics professional turned Front-End Developer. Skilled in creating intuitive & responsive applications using various front-end technologies, and I also share my projects and insights on trends in front-end development and design through my personal brand on social media.

### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

## **Front-End Development**

- Developed multiple front-end mock websites using design files and assets to simulate real world front-end practices.
- Adhere to specific design specifications to produce accurate applications to simulate client-side design satisfaction.
- Developed interactive and user friendly applications using React and SCSS that incorporated UI/UX design principles.

## Website Design & Development

- Designed, developed, & deployed my own website showcasing my projects and skills as a developer.
- Incorporated Google Analytics A4 to monitor and increase website traffic by 200% and steadily increase weekly page views by 15%.
- Promoted my website to various social media platforms, such as LinkedIn, Instagram, and Twitter to increase traffic and exposure among users, companies, and various developers.

## **REST API Development**

- Developed a RESTful API using TypeScript, Express, and Node, implementing best practices for architecture and HTTP requests.
- Developed familiarity with HTTP requests to handle calls to the API efficiently and prevent potential errors.
- Implement API documentation to enhance clarity & convenience to correctly navigate and use the API.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Frontier Supply Chain Solutions** – Logistics Specialist

SEPT 2021 - DEC 2022

- Utilized software systems to track and monitor shipments.
- Communicated with commercial drivers and vendors to ensure accurate and timely delivery of goods ensuring punctual clearance time.
- Cleared over 200+ commercial freight deliveries crossing state borders, with an average of approximately 10 deliveries a day.

## **ZARA**, — Sales Associate

NOV 2018 - JUL 2020

- Streamlined check-out process by utilizing efficient floor maintenance techniques resulting in 50% increase in productivity amongst team members.
- Effectively increased productivity by 20% training new employees on daily store tasks and procedures.
- Consistently boosted daily revenue with peak-hour sales promotion by 25%.

Seattle, WA

## nyrell.leonor2000@gmail.com

(206) 661-2450

https://www.nyrellcl.com LinkedIn Github

### **SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React
- Node
- REST API
- Git

#### **EDUCATION**

Shoreline Community College *Purchasing*,

Procurement/Acquisitions and Contracts Management - 2021 2022

Seattle Pacific University
Department of Psychology 2018- 2019

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Coursera - React Basics

**Coursera** - Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

**Coursera** – Programming with JavaScript

Coursera - Version Control

Coursera – HTML & CSS In Depth

**Coursera** - Introduction to Front-end Development

**Google** - Google Analytics A4 Certification